Guide to the Gail W. Lapidus Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gail W. Lapidus papers
1963-2010
SC1059
Lapidus, Gail W.
19 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was donated by Gail W. Lapidus to Stanford University, Special Collections in MONTH 2011
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Gail Lapidus is a Senior Fellow Emerita at the Institute for International Studies at Stanford University. Lapidus is also Professor Emerita of Political Science at the University of California, Berkeley, and served as Chair of the Berkeley-Stanford Program in Soviet and Post-Soviet Studies from 1985 to 1994. A specialist on Soviet society, politics and foreign policy, she has authored and edited a number of books on Soviet and post-Soviet affairs, including The New Russia: Troubled Transformation (Westview Press, 1995), From Union to Commonwealth: Nationalism and Separatism in the Soviet Republics, with Victor Zaslavsky and Philip Goldman (Cambridge University Press, 1992), The Soviet System in Crisis, with Alexander Dallin (Westview, 1992), and Women in Soviet Society (University of California Press, 1979). A graduate of Radcliffe College, she received her MA and PhD from Harvard University.
Lapidus is also the author of numerous articles and chapters, including "The War in Chechnya as a Paradigm of Russian State-Building Under Putin," Post-Soviet Affairs, March 2004; "Putin's War on Terrorism: Lessons From Chechnya," Post-Soviet Affairs, January-March 2002; "Accommodating Ethnic Differences in Post-Soviet Eurasia," in Crawford Young and Mark Beissinger, eds., Beyond State Crisis? Post-Colonial Africa and Post-Soviet Eurasia in Comparative Perspective; "Transforming the 'National Question': New Approaches to Nationalism, Federalism and Sovereignty," in Archie Brown, ed., The Demise of Marxism-Leninism in Russia (Palgrave, 2004); "Transforming Russia: American Policy in the 1990s," in Robert Lieber, ed., America Rules? Foreign Policy and American Primacy in the 21st Century (Prentice Hall, 2001); and "Reagan and the Russians: American Policy Toward the Soviet Union," with Alexander Dallin, in Kenneth Oye et al., eds., Eagle Resurgent? The Reagan Era in American Foreign Policy (Little, Brown, 1987).
Lapidus is a member of the Council of Foreign Relations, as well as of several scholarly associations. She has held a variety of scholarly and administrative appointments, including president of the American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, chair of the Social Science Research Council's Joint Committee on Soviet Studies, the Advisory Council of the Woodrow Wilson Center's Kennan Institute, the Committee on International Political Science of the American Political Science Association, and the board of Trustees of the World Affairs Council of Northern California. She has held research fellowships at the Kennan Institute of the Woodrow Wilson Center in Washington, at the Harriman Institute at Columbia University and at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford. A frequent visitor to the USSR and now to a number of successor states, Professor Lapidus is currently working on a book on the impact of the Soviet legacy on patterns of conflict in the post-Soviet states.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist primarily of research files containing both articles (in English and printed in Cyrillic - exact Slavic language unknown, but presumably Russian) and drafts of papers on the Soviet Union from as early as 1966 and as late as the early 2000s. The general themes include nationalism, ethnicity, federalism, and gender in the Soviet states. There are a great many files dedicated to various organizations dealing with international relations and Soviet studies.
Access Terms
Nationalism--Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation)--History.; Soviet Union--Ethnic relations.; Women's rights--Soviet Union.
Collection Contents
- Research and subject files, 1970-2010; Accession ARCH-2011-327
  - Research Files
    - USIA Polls (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Russ Survey 97 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - VTsIOM - Surveys (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Vchiom Interchentr Akademiya Narodiogo Ghozyaystva (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Russian Duma Election (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Leninskaya Nachionachnaya Politika i Nachionalinie Otnosheniya v SSSR v Period Razvitogo Sochializma (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - PhD Theses: Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Library of Congress Bibliographies (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Table of Contents: Soviet Journals (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Table of Contents: Soviet Books (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Western Bibliography on USSR (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Western Bibliography on Comparative Ethnography (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Western Periodicals (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Comments at AAASS Panel on Nationalities (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Harpers Paper (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Analytical Tables (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Czarist Nationality Policy (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Lapidus - Appointment as Graduate Advisor (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Superfin, Gabriel (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Survey - IR Research Community - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Graduate Work Political Science (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Conference on Soviet Cities (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - American Committee on East-West Accord (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - East-West Community Resources Catherine Menninger (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Lectures on Soviet Nationality Policy (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Columbia Seminar: Nationality Lecture (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Books and Articles to Review (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Lapidus Bibliography: Kennan (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Dutter Project (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Materials in German (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Slavic Bibliographical Aids (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Simmons Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Soviet Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Iudina Bibliography: to 1973 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Conferences 1985-86 Slavic Center (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Slavic Dept. (Joan) (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Center Exec Comm (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Executive Committee October 81 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Audience Lists (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - SF Committee on Foreign Relations (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - McLaughlin File (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Visiting Appointments (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Funding East European Programs Ford Foundation (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Cohen, Elliott (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Confino (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Area Centers - Information (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Possible Members - Slavic Center Executive Committee (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Hosting Visiting Scholars FULBRIGHT (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Open Window, TV Series (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Report of President's Commission on Foreign Languages and International Studies November 1979 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Legislation Affecting Program (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Development Office (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Sovset (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Main Library (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Library - Report of Edward Kasinec's Trip - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Library MA's (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Library (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - UC - Stanford Cooperation: Libraries (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - "Unofficial" Groups (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Oblast' Press (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Soviet Samizdat - Hoover Listings (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - 1981 Records (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - National Council for Soviet and East European Research - Consortium (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Jess: Title VIII Application (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Social Science Research Council (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Annual Report of the Center for Slavic And East European Studies 1983-4 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - JCSS (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - JCSS (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Meeting of May 20-21, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Outline of Application for the Support of Activites of JCSS (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Meeting of October 1, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - SSRC Committee - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Getty Letter - 25 March 1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Meeting: February 1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - JCSS Fund Letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Minutes of May Meeting (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Cultural Revolution (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Modernization and Sex Roles (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Occupational Segregation (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Overview (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Socialism and the Chinese Family (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Current Digest (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Review Article on Social Stratification in USSR (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Social Science and Public Policy: Bibliography, Syllabi (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Soviet Sociology, Western Articles (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Soviet Sociology: Soviet Articles (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Literaturnaia Gazeva (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Education, Industrialization, and Social Change (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Sharpe Volume (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Comparative Education volume: Sexual Equality via Educational Reform (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Publishers Contracts (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Studying Soviet Society (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Impact of US-USSR Exchanges (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Female Industrial Labor (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Multinationality and the Survival of the Soviet Political System: Stablizing and Destabilizing Factors (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Soviet Family Sociology (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - India Contacts (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Social Equality: USA/USSR (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - The Stanford Central Asian Initiative (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Wolff, David (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Sovsio Logischeskie Issledovaniia (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - To File (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Sexual Equality USSR: General Soviet Articles (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - On Equality (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Weber, Steve (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Mueller, Julie Kay (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Social Stratification, USSR - Western Articles (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Cartoons and Jokes (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Soviet Women: New Materials (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Miscellanea to File (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Soviet Education (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Shulgin Books and Articles (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Materials for Department (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Women in Industrial Society: General Articles (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Lowenthal, Richard - Development vs. Utopia in Communist Policy (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - China - Sociology Colloquium (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - MacArthur (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Zev Katz Papers (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Maps (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - McArthur - 99 Summer Conference (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - USIA Repts. Lists (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - TICA - Eurasia Newsletter (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Kuchins - FSU List '97 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - The Heritage Foundation Backgrounder Executive Summary - June 18, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Casp. Conf. - Grovel (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - GAIL- VISAS (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - VR - Tbilisi (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Invites Casp. 5/99 communication (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Vadim (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Rockefeller - Final rep. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - 96-97 reports to Carnegie (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - NBR Receives USIP Grant to Study Energy and Conflict (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Carnegie News-Info (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - MacArthur - Final - Orig. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - A. Gegeslidze - Proposal (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Caspian Basin Proposal (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Grepous - Georg. Nat. Sec. Concept (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Proposals - Other (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Proposals - CISAC (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Fall 1978 - Readings (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Soviet Education: Trans. of Bubnov P. Directives (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Anweiler Translation (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - CV (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Perspective (Boston U.) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Politics of Sov. Economic Reform (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Postfactum (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Rand/UCLA (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Russian Monitor (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - RFE/RL Sov/E European Report (1991) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Soros Foundation (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Transition (World Bank) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Ukrainian Weekly (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - US Inst. of Peace (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Association for the Study of Nationalities (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Baltic News (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - B-S PSS Chronicle (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - CIS Environmental Watch (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Christian Democracy (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - CSIS (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Ctr for Naval Analyses (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Deutsche Bank (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Harriman Institute (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Inst. for East-West Security Studies (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Kennan Institute (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Nat. and Siberian Studies (Harriman) (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Ethnicity/Conflict (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Violence as Nationalist Contention (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - On Ethnic Composition of Population of the Georgian Republic; Rossiyskiy Nyezavisimiy Institut Sotsialnikh i Natsionalnikh Problem (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Regional Economic Development (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - KPSS v Resoliutsiiakh i Resheniiakh J'ezdov Konferentsii i Plenumov Tsk (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Migration and Labor Resources (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Central Asians Lobby for Additional Water Resources (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Zimmer Papers (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Andropov and Policy (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Chernenko and Policy (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Soviet Economy in Regional Perspectives (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - River Diversion (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Nechemias: Regional Diff. w/in RSFSR (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Bahry/Nechemias (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Economic Equalization: Western Writings (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Economic Equalization: Soviet Views (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Soviet Studies Jan. 1966 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Socialism and the National Question (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Lenin on the National Question (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Stalin and the National Question (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Stalin: Marxism and the Natl-Col. Quest (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Soviet Anniversary (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Brezhnev and the National Question (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Andropov on the National Question (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - 60th Anniversary Speeches and Writings (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Bio-Bib for '79-'80: June 1980 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence - Dossier 79-80 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - COR Grant 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - IIS Project & Budget (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Political Participation (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence Jan. 1980- (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Tbilisi Conference (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Yerevan Workshop (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - WAC Conf. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Invitations - Caspian (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Russ Fed Conf - 5/98 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Frowick, 4/00 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - E. Morris April '00 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Nordquist - Hewlett (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Tbilisi '98 - Conf. rept. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - David/Nerses WPs (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Casp. Conf. Rept. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - David/Nerses Papers (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Rubin: Conflict of Interests (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Chech - Carnegie 8/99 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Petrov Visit 1-99 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Barnett Rubin (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Oskamian (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Georgia Parliamentary Delegation - Visit to Stanford (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Zvonia (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Georgian Visit, March 29/30, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - CISAC Spr. 98 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Kulikov 6/98 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Hewlett Grant (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Caspian Conf. Misc. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Leokadia workshop (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Russia: Regions, Ethnicity and Federalism (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Tbilisi Conf. Article, sum. '98 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - CA trip 1997 - prog & notes (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Intimations of Multipolarity (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Identities in Transition: Eastern Europe and Russia After the Collapse of Communism (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Michael Rywkin: Russia and the Former USSR (First Draft) (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Democracy and Dichotomies (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Gradations of Democracy? (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Pastor: Mediating Elections (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Core and Periphery in Post-Cold War Europe (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Violence and the Social Construction of Ethnic Identities (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Russia Turns the Corner (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Making Progress on a Fissile Material Cutoff Treaty After the South Asian Tests (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - The Meanings of Union (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - The Political Economy of the Resource Curse (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Challenging the "Correct" Line - Jowitt (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Nezavisimaya Gazeta 18.07.97 Posle Yada - Pulya (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - East European Constitutional Review (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Diagrams (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Freedom in the "Democratic Age" (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - How Can Permanent Cessation of Civil Wars be Achieved? - Fortna (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Civ. Conflicts - Comp. (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - The Causes of Corruption: A Cross-National Study (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Greisman (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Russ. and Federalism (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Solnick (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - A Shadow Middle Class for a Shadow Economy (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - E.W. Walker Draft '98 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Stavzakis - Waller (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Peoples Against States: Ethnopolitical Conflict and the Changing World System (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - S. Tsalik Dissert. Dft. (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Chronology 1945-1960 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - C. Tilly Papers (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Oksenberg - China (12/99) (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Seminar on Democratization Institute for International Studies (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Melville (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Melville (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Cent. Asia - Conflict Res. Articles (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Diamond - Dem (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Postsocialist Pathways (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Schmitter - Dem. (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Ending Civil Wars (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - S. Walt - IS - Spr. 99 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Foreign Affairs Articles (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Smith (ed.) chs. 1, 9 (1998) (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - O. Grinevsky (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Solnick (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - J. Wedel 1999 (2000 Russ.) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Dunlop - Dagerton (2000) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Dunlop (N. Cauc. '00) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Conference Reports (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - German-American Conference June 1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Dienes Paper (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Lubrano, Linda Review of Article (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on the German-American Seminar (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Prytanean Honor Society (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Pan Am Rebate (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "Social Conservatism" Paper (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Fainsod Seminar Papers (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Report on Poli Sci Dept. Fall 80 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Bio-Bib for '78-'79: June 1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - 1978-1979 Info for Bio Bib (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Poli Sci 141A: W '81 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Workshop: Bibliography, Possible Participants (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Soviet and East European Studies in the United States (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Grad Student Affirmative Action (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - International Fellowship Programme for Advanced Soviet and East European Studies (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Carnegie Consultant (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Preventing Nuclear Conflict: What Can the Behavioral Sciences Contribute? (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Issue Area and Foreign Policy Analysis (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Notes (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Papers on Ethnic Groups (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Fellowships (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - 3rd World Congress: Basile Kerblay (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Besack, Michael (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Soviet and East European Studies in the United States (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Final Program (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Prewitt Paper (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Sino Soviet Conference (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Sino-Soviet Project (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Coordinated Proposal re: legislation (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Soviet-EE Research & Training Act 1983 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Legislation & Joint Proposal (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Ford Foundation Project Reviews (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Ideas for Field (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - About Education (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Exchanges (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Rand News Release (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Soviet Bloc Research and Training Act of 1982 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Power and Poverty Notes (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - The Soviet Policy-Making Process: A Research Agenda (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Conference on Soviet Decisionmaking For Natl Security (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Program on Soviet International Behavior (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Berkeley: Development Office (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Extended Empire (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Bird: JCSS (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - JCSS Meeting -- April 1985 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - JCSS Handbook (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - JCSS April 85 Meeting (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - JCSS Title VIII Proposal (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - House Co-Sponsors of H.R. 601 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Federal Legislation (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Overseers Committee to Visit the Harvard Russian Research Center (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - "Multinationality and the Survival..." (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - "The Nationality Question and..." The Soviet Union in the 1980s, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - History and Background Materials (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Title VIII Request for Proposals (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - "Contemporary Soviet Decision Making" Policy Process Paper (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Occupational Segregation and Public Policy Signs, Spring 1976 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - "The Brezhnev Regime and Directed..." The 25th Congress of the CPSU, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - "Changing Soviet Perspectives and Policies" Pacific-Asian Issues, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - "Society Under Strain" The Washington Quarterly, Spring 1983 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - "Reagan and the Russians: American..." Eagle Resurgent? 1986 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Reagan and the Russians: American Policy Toward the Soviet Union (Revised) (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Current Materials JCSS (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - JCSS - Title VIII Grant Agreement (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - SSRC Sept 83 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Social Trends (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Women in Soviet Society (Manuscript) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Gender and Restructuring: The Impact..." Democratic Reform and the... (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - To File in a Stock Book (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The New Russia (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The New Russia (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Liberalization Without Liberals? Communism in Transition (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Nationalism, Ethnic Identity and Conflict Mgmt. in Russia Today (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - 6/95 Monitor, Chechnya Factsheet, etc. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Conf. Papers - OLD (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - The End of the Cold War is Also Over (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Gail's Copies (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Editing Paper Drafts (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Maresca (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Maresca - Printing (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Ethnic Conflict Project General/Background Info (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Russian Elections Workshop 4/96 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Historical Documents (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - BSP - First Meeting (Box 9, Folder 20)